# DENISE BAKER

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

I am a professional violinist with a career spanning over 25 years. In the music industry, I have had many exciting experiences and opportunities including performances in Carnegie Hall, European and American tours, music videos, and winning Grammy awards as a member of the Nashville Symphony. Over the last few years I've been plagued with shoulder injuries and decided to pursue one of my hobbies more seriously. I have always been interested in software development and when I found out about the Nashville Software School, I jumped at the opportunity. I am looking forward to a career in a field where creativity and perpetual learning are a must to succeed

- 615-260-4570
- ✓ denviol125@gmail.com
- github.com/denzelb5
- denise-baker.firebaseapp.com
- in linkedin.com/in/denise-e-baker

Pvthon

#### **TECH STACK**

- React.js
- JavaScriptjQuery
- HTML
- C#
- CSS
   Visual Studio Code
- Bootstrap
   Git & Github

# PERSONAL PROJECTS GIGMEISTER -- Front-End Capstone

GigMeister is a single page application that allows symphonic musicians to keep track of their gigs /events. A user can create an event, choose the needed instrumentation, and then assign players to the event based on the instrumentation. It is a data driven app allowing the user to create a roster for an ensemble of anywhere from 2 - 200+ players. Utilizing full CRUD, it allows the user to edit their events as needed. Future plans include expense tracking, calendar, frequent / repeated event

tracking, and player response tracking.
https://github.com/denzelb5/gig
https://gigmeister-999cc.firebaseapp.com

### **EDUCATION**

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL Software Developer Bootcamp

UNIVERSITY OF NORTH CAROLINA SCHOOL OF THE ARTS M.M & B.M -- Music Performance

#### TECHNICAL EDUCATION

# NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL Full-Stack Software Developer

Sept 2019 - present

One year part-time bootcamp focusing on React, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS, as well as C# and SQL server-side concepts.

- Developed single page applications using React and Javascript, emphasizing reusable components and DRY, modular code
- Implemented version control and project management using Git and GitHub project boards and issue tracking
- Planned database designs with entity relationship diagrams to map table relationships and ensure flat data structure
- Practiced deployment of applications with Firebase
- Created a Restful Web API called ClinkedIn using .NET framework
- Developed multiple C# Console applications utilizing LINQ queries, RegEx, and XUnit
- Test Driven Development using C#
- Developed T-SQL queries using SQL Server Management Studio

# GROUP PROJECTS NUTSHELL NAUTILUS EXPLORER

Collaborated with 2 teammates to create a single page, ship database management application using React, JavaScript, Bootstrap, and Firebase for persistent data storage

 Implemented full CRUD functionality for the destinations component as well as partial CRUD for the crew and logs components

github.com/nss-evening-cohort-10/nutshell-nautilus-explorer

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NASHVILLE SYMPHONY 1st Violin, 4th Chair Sept. 1996 - Present

Professional grammy award winning symphony orchestra

- Performances involve real time decision-making and simultaneous collaboration with teams of 20 - 150 people
- Symphonic playing requires great attention to detail and concise, yet clear communication
- As permanent 4th chair, duties included frequently stepping into leadership roles of Associate Concertmaster and Concertmaster
- Facilitate and coordinate cross-functionally to achieve desired results

VANDERBILT UNIVERSITY Blair School of Music Adjunct Professor of Violin 1998 -2012

### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Winner of 13 Grammy Awards as member of Nashville Symphony
- Performances in Carnegie Hall and throughout the Europe.
- Performances as featured soloist with the Nashville Philharmonic, Nashville Concerto Orchestra, and the Western Piedmont Symphony.
- Numerous commercial recordings with artists such as Garth Brooks, Taylor Swift, Carrie Underwood and Matchbox Twenty.
- Performances on movie soundtrack Bridget Jones Diary and Tim McGraw music video.